Guide to the Samuel Silver accounts, 1859-1901.
Silver, Samuel accounts, 1859-1901.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Samuel Silver accounts, 1859-1901.
2269
Samuel Silver.
13 v., 150 items
Record books, a treasurer's book, vouchers, genealogical information, a photograph, correspondence, a pamphlet, and other papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Business and personal papers of Samuel Silver, a glass-blower in Clayton N.J., including record books in which he listed accounts received for blowing glass. Also, a treasurer's book, 1890, for the glass bottle workers' union, Local Assembly #406, National Trade Assembly #143 of the Knights of Labor, and payment authorization vouchers; genealogical information on the Silver family; photograph of Samuel Silver, Sr.; and photocopied miscellaneous Silver family letters. Also, "Silver Notes from South Jersey" by Samuel F. Silver, 1992.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Business and personal papers of Samuel Silver, a glass-blower in Clayton N.J., including record books in which he listed accounts received for blowing glass. Also, a treasurer's book, 1890, for the glass bottle workers' union, Local Assembly #406, National Trade Assembly #143 of the Knights of Labor, and payment authorization vouchers; genealogical information on the Silver family; photograph of Samuel Silver, Sr.; and photocopied miscellaneous Silver family letters. Also, "Silver Notes from South Jersey" by Samuel F. Silver, 1992.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Silver, Samuel.; Silver, Samuel F., Silver Notes from South Jersey.; Knights of Labor.; National Trade Assembly.
Subjects:
Glass-blowing.
Places:
Clayton (N.J.)--Commerce.
Form and Genre Terms:
Account books.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Account books
  NOTE: Most of the account books contain two types of entries: expenditures for groceries, household goods and supplies, clothing, drygoods, etc., in front of books; receipts mainly for glass blowing in back of books.
  - Glass blowing receipts; firm not named. No expenditures for household, etc. Birth dates of three children noted down; year of daughter's birth not same as on loose item in folder (1860?, 1861?)., Aug. 1859-May 1861 (Volume 1)
  - John M. Moore & Company., Oct. 1862-Apr. 1865 (Volume 2)
  - Moore Brothers. Dealers in Dry Goods, Groceries, Queensware, Boots & Shoes, Provisions, etc., Fislerville [later Clayton], N.J., Apr. 1865-Aug. 1867 (Volume 3)
  - Moore Brothers., Sept. 1867-Mar. 1869 (Volume 4)
  - Moore Brothers., June 1870-Dec. 1872 (Volume 5)
  - Moore Brothers., Apr. 1875-June 1877 (Volume 6)
  - Moore Brothers., July 1877-Oct. 1879 (Volume 7)
  - Moore Brothers., Oct. 1881-Sept. 1883 (Volume 8)
  - Fisler & Morgan Company, groceries, etc.; Woodbury Glass Works, glass blowing., Sept. 1883-Oct. 1886 (Volume 9)
  - Moore Brothers., Nov. 1886-July 1887 (Volume 10)
  - F.M. Pierce & Company., Sept. 1888-Sept. 1891 (Volume 11)
  - Woodbury Glass Works. Glass blowing receipts only., Sept. 1896-Mar. 1901 (Volume 12)
- Other papers
  - Bills from tax collectors, doctors, dentists, jewelers, undertakers (n.d. May 3, 1882: casket, black merino shroud), confectioners, coal dealers, clothing stores, sewing machine salesman (Singer--$55), papering and painting, lumber, etc. Name DuBois appears on several bills or receipts--perhaps son-in-law., 1869-1900 (Folder 1)
  - Recipe for ham cure. (Folder 1)
  - Remedy for rheumatism. (Folder 1)
  - Note giving birth day of the three Silver Children (1857, 1861 [?], 1863). (Folder 1)
  - Treasurer's book of Local Assembly No. 406; 4 pp. only filled. (This organization was the local of the glass bottle workers' union, National Trade Assembly #143 of the Knights of Labor. Pertinent corres. and Xeroxes from selected pp. of Proceedings on file in this folder.), Feb.-Dec. 1890 (Volume 13)
  - Payment vouchers (61 items, Nos. 25-85) authorizing Silver, as treasurer of the organization, to pay stated sum to a certain person, in most cases, George P. Pierce., Feb. 18, 1890-July 7, 1891 (Folder 2)
  - 4 loose sheets of calculations and notes concerning dues and assessments., n.d. (Folder 2)
  - Receipt., 1890 (Folder 2)
  - 10 bills., ca. 1894-1900